mlsstratus.com 2019-06-27

# Privacy Policy

* * *

### LIBOR TAKES YOUR PRIVACY SERIOUSLY.

Please read the following to learn more about our Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy may be updated from time to time so please check back frequently. Your use of this website constitutes your acceptance of this Privacy Policy.

LIBOR is committed to your privacy and security, and wants to provide you with the best possible online experience. To that end, we want you to understand what kinds of information we gather from you, how this information is used and safeguarded, and how you can control its use.

### This Privacy Policy covers the following issues:

**What information is collected from me?**

The kinds of information we collect from you will vary, depending on how you use our websites. Sometimes we will collect personally identifiable information ("Personal Information"). For example, if you choose to take advantage of some of our products and services, you may be asked to provide information such as a user name and password, your real name, e-mail address, phone number, address, your real estate license or MLS ID# or, for certain e-commerce transactions, your credit card information. 

In addition to the Personal Information you choose to submit, our systems are set up to gather certain data to help us to better understand how the site is being used and how we can improve it. This data may not be linked to you personally. This automatically gathered data includes your computer's "Internet Protocol" ("IP") address, statistics about how visitors navigate through our site and information provided through the use of cookies and web beacons (which is described in more detail below).

Finally, as you visit our site, be aware that third parties may at times be able to gather information from you. For example, third party marketing companies and ad servers may use their own cookies, and companies offering products or services through LIBOR sites may use their own cookies and may collect and use the information you submit. In these cases, the third parties may use your information according to their own privacy policies, which may differ from this Privacy Policy.

**How is my information used?**

LIBOR may use the information to:

\- Improve and customize the content and layout of our sites and other communications tools

\- Send you e-mail news updates

\- Notify you of relevant products and services

\- Track usage of our sites

\- Provide more relevant advertising on other websites

\- Notify you of upcoming LIBOR events and programs

The use of your information depends on the context in which it is collected. The following sections describe in more detail the type of information that is collected and how it is used.

Additionally, we will disclose personal information when we believe in good faith that such disclosures (a) are required by law, including, for example, to comply with a court order or subpoena, or (b) will help to: enforce our policies; protect your safety or security, including the safety and security of property that belongs to you; and/or, protect the safety and security of our Site(s) or third parties.

### Cookies, Web Beacons, and similar technology

These are small files that are sent to and stored on your computer so that we and third parties that provide services for our sites can recognize your computer as a unique machine the next time you visit our sites. This technology is used to keep track of your information for your own convenience; help us optimize your online experience by altering our content depending on your particular needs or browsing patterns; provide you with advertisements (on and off our site), products and services potentially of interest to you; help us understand the size of our audience and their traffic patterns within our network; and help us pursue similar goals. Some of our advertisers and third-party ad servers may also utilize their own cookies, web beacons, and similar technologies, which are subject to their own privacy policies. Also, companies offering products or services through LIBOR websites may use their own cookies, which are subject to their own privacy policies.

**Registration**

The information you provide when you become a registered user to certain pages of our site is used primarily to help us customize your online experience. Your e-mail address serves as a unique identifier in our record system, and it is used together with your password to prevent unauthorized access to any information you choose to store on our sites. The data you give us about your personal preferences and demographics (such as age, zip code, occupation, or other data) may be used to help us offer content, advertisements, products and services that are most likely to appeal to you. In addition, we may share this information, in aggregate form, with our current and potential advertisers so they can know how to present their ads more effectively. By registering with any LIBOR website, you are confirming that you are at least 18 years old or older.

Unless you specify that you'd prefer not to hear from us, we may also use the e-mail address you provide at registration to contact you for promotional, administrative, or other reasons. You may have these communications terminated at any time. If you indicate that you're interested in hearing from other companies, we may also share your contact information for that purpose.

**Tools**

Our sites allow you to use many helpful tools, such as financial and home improvements calculators, real estate search tools, and others, without disclosing any Personal Information. These tools are for your benefit and the information you submit when you use them (typically impersonal data) is not disclosed to anyone or used for any purpose other than to provide you with the service you're seeking.

**Registered User Services**

You may choose to request products or services of a more substantial or personal nature when using our websites. You may store your preferences for convenience in using our sites, or make an online purchase. The information you provide when seeking these services may be used in the following ways.

For services provided by LIBOR websites, the information you submit is used by us to provide the service you've requested. We may also share this information with subcontractors, but only to the extent necessary to fulfill your request. In addition, we may use the contact information and nonfinancial order information you've supplied, such as your e-mail address, as set out in the Registration section above. If the service you request requires submission of financial information such as credit card number for an online purchase, rest assured that this financial information is used only for processing your payment, and is not retained after completion of your order unless you have given us the authority to make automatic payments on your credit card. In that event, your credit card information will be retained by us until you cancel your automatic payments. We may, however, store your nonfinancial order information for accounting purposes and to help us to understand your preferences better so that we can offer you future products or services that you may find useful.

**Credit Information**

Credit information that you and credit authorizers provide when you make payments by credit card for products or other services will only be used to process the transactions you request. This information will be provided to and maintained by reputable credit reporting databases, but will never be sold, shared or provided to other third parties.

**Purchasing Products And Managing Your Services**

For products and services offered to you jointly by LIBOR and a third party, your information may be shared with or independently gathered by the third party. You can tell when a product or service is offered by a third party, because a page of our site will be "co-branded" displaying the third party's logo and/or name along with our own, or you will be linked to the third party's site to complete the transaction.

Third parties have their own policies regarding the use and protection of your information that may differ from those outlined in this Privacy Policy. If you are concerned about how your Personal Information might be used or protected by a third party, we encourage you to become familiar with that company's privacy policy before using the service or requesting the product, or to not request the particular product or service.

**Solicited Information**

You may occasionally see sweepstakes, surveys and other features of our site that ask you to provide us with Personal Information. When you choose to respond to these requests, the Personal Information you offer may be used for several purposes. These include the uses set out in the Registration section above. They also include providing information to third parties as necessary for prize fulfillment and other aspects of any sweepstake or similar offerings.

**User Initiated Communication**

Our websites enable you to e-mail us or third parties and to participate in public bulletin boards and discussion groups. Whenever you choose to initiate these kinds of communication with us, or anyone else, you may expect to be contacted in return.

**Automatically Gathered Data**

The information gathered automatically by our system—such as your computer's IP address, the kind of browser you're using, a record of your navigation through our site, and information obtained through cookies and web beacons—may be used by LIBOR so we can understand how to make our sites convenient and useful to our audience, in addition to the other ways outlined in this Privacy Policy. In addition, we may share this information with our current and potential advertisers so they can know how to present their advertisements more effectively.

**Advertising**

Some of our sites contain advertising placed by advertising networks pursuant to agreement between LIBOR and the advertising network. We do not control these advertising networks, the sites of third parties reached through links on our site, or their information collection practices. LIBOR is not responsible for the activities of these third parties. Third party advertisers may collect information from you that may be personally identifiable, and the third party advertisers may conduct behavioral advertising.

Additionally, we employ a third party ad service to help provide relevant ads to you on and off this site. Please see below ("How do I "opt out"?") to opt out of such ad targeting.

### How do I "opt out" and limit information gathering?

You also have the ability to terminate e-mail newsletter correspondence from us at any time. You will either be given the chance to opt-out of direct mailings when you disclose your e-mail address to us or you can simply reply to our e-mail typing "Unsubscribe" in the subject line, or e-mail the appropriate webmaster below with your request and we will promptly remove your address from that e-mail service:[info@LIREALTOR.com](mailto:info@mlsli.com)

If you feel concerned about the cookies that are sent between our computers and yours, you may, through your Web browser, either choose to reject them automatically, or have your computer prompt you before accepting them. Generally, this is done by selecting the appropriate cookies setting on your Web browser (usually found in "Internet Options" or "Preferences"). Please note, however, that some of our features and services depend on the use of cookies. Therefore, you will be unable to take advantage of those features if you choose not to accept cookies.

Additionally, you may opt out of our third party marketing company's collection and use of data on our behalf at[www.reachlocal.com/opt-out](http://www.reachlocal.com/opt-out) and [www.reachlocal.com/trackingopt-out](http://www.reachlocal.com/trackingopt-out).

Third party advertisers and websites may collect information from you and provide advertising based on that information. To opt out of such advertising from companies that are part of the Network Advertising Initiative, please go to <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>.

Additionally, you can find more information about "do not track" options at [http://www.allaboutdnt.com](http://www.allaboutdnt.com/).

### How is my information protected?

Whenever Personal Information about you is stored on our computers, that information is password-protected from unauthorized access or use. In addition, this information is kept only on servers that are located behind a firewall. 

We have additional security measures for financial information. We will only transmit or ask for this information over secure Internet connections, using SSL (Secure Sockets Layer) encryption, the currently accepted standard for online security, and security keys. In addition, we require password authentication from any third parties you've authorized to receive this information. Finally, your credit card number and financial information are never stored on our servers. While this means you may have to enter this information more than once, we believe the added security is worth the extra effort. 

Of course, we appreciate your help in safeguarding the integrity of your own and others' privacy. We hope you'll use common sense whenever you disclose Personal Information over the Internet. Just as importantly, we encourage you to let us know immediately if you suspect that the information you share with us is being used in any way contrary to this Privacy Policy. To contact us, please send an e-mail to:[info@LIREALTOR.com](mailto:info@mlsli.com).

**Scope of This Privacy Policy: Outside Links**

This Privacy Policy only applies to sites owned and operated by LIBOR. Our pages contain links to sites outside our control. Please be aware that these sites may collect information about you, and operate according to their own privacy practices that may differ from this Privacy Policy. Remember that once you're outside our websites, any information you submit is outside of our control. 

**Contacting Us**

If you have concerns about this Privacy Policy or our privacy practices, contact us at: 

Privacy Administrator - LIREALTOR.com   
300 Sunrise Highway   
West Babylon, New York 11704   
Fax 631-661-5202   
E-mail: [info@LIREALTOR.com](mailto:info@mlsli.com)

### Revision Date: June 17, 2014
